Yiren Jian

Research Scientist

ByteDance Inc.

🛮 yiren.jian.gr@dartmouth.edu 📗 🧥 yiren-jian.github.io 📗 🖫 yiren-jian

I am a research scientist at TikTok. My current research focuses on **multimodal large language models** (MLLMs) and **vision-language models** (VLMs) for advanced understanding. I have contributed to the pretraining of generative vision-language models, and I am actively working on the development of multimodal language models for math and STEM domains.

Professional Experience

Research Scientist, TikTok (ByteDance Inc.)

Bellevue, WA

Develop multimodal language models for math and STEM domains.

Sept. 2024 - Now

Manager: Zhenheng Yang

Research Scientist, ByteDance Inc.

Bellevue, WA

Develop open-sourced visual language models for multimodal understanding.

Feb. 2024 - Sept. 2024

Manager: Hongxia Yang

Research Scientist Intern, ByteDance Inc.

Bellevue, WA

Develop efficient generative visual-language models based on LLM.

June. 2023 - Sept. 2023

Advisor: Yunzhe Tao

Research Scientist Intern, Snap Research at Snap Inc.

Palo Alto, CA

Develop neural speakers for affective image captioning.

June. 2022 - Sept. 2022

Advisor: Panos Achlioptas

Research Scientist Intern, NEC Labs America

Princeton, NJ (remote)

 ${\it Develop~physical-augmented~ML~models~for~precision~immunotherapy}.$

June. 2021 - Sept. 2021

Advisor: Martin Renqiang Min

Education

Dartmouth College Hanover, NH, USA

Doctor of Philosophy - Computer Science Sept. 2018 - Jan. 2024

Advisor: Soroush Vosoughi

The George Washington University

Washington DC, USA

Master of Science - Biophysics Sept. 2015 - May. 2017

Advisor: Chen Zeng

Huazhong University of Science and Technology

Wuhan, China

Bachelor of Science - Physics Sept. 2011 - May. 2015

Thesis advisor: Yi Xiao

Publications

Working Memory Identifies Reasoning Limits in Language Models

[EMNLP 2024] The 2024 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing

Chunhui Zhang, Yiren Jian, Zhongyu Ouyang, Soroush Vosoughi

InfiMM-WebMath-40B: Advancing Multimodal Pre-Training for Enhanced Mathematical Reasoning

preprint

Xiaotian Han[#] and **Yiren Jian**[#] and Xuefeng Hu[#] and Haogeng Liu[#] and Yiqi[#] Wang and Qihang Fan and Yuang Ai and Huaibo Huang and Ran He and Zhenheng Yang and Quanzeng You

InfiMM: Advancing Multimodal Understanding with an Open-Sourced Visual Language Model

[Findings of ACL 2024] Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics

Haogeng Liu, Quanzeng You, Yiqi Wang, Xiaotian Han, Bohan Zhai, Yongfei Liu, Wentao Chen, **Yiren Jian**, Yunzhe Tao, Jianbo Yuan, Ran He, Hongxia Yang

Expedited Training of Visual Conditioned Language Generation via Redundancy Reduction

[ACL 2024, * oral presentation] The 62nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics

Yiren Jian, Tingkai Liu, Yunzhe Tao, Chunhui Zhang, Soroush Vosoughi, Hongxia Yang

GEM: Generating Engaging Multimodal Content

[IJCAI 2024] International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence

Chongyang Gao, Yiren Jian, Natalia Denisenko, Soroush Vosoughi, V.S. Subrahmanian

Efficient and Effective Learning of Foundational Large Multi-Modal Models

Dartmouth College PhD Dissertations, 2024

Yiren Jian

RNet: a network strategy to predict RNA binding preferences

Briefings in Bioinformatics, 2024

Haoquan Liu, **Yiren Jian**, Jinxuan Hou, Ceng Zeng, Yunjie Zhao

Knowledge from Large-Scale Protein Contact Prediction Models Can Be Transferred to the Data-Scarce RNA Contact Prediction Task

[ICPR 20224] International Conference on Pattern Recognition, 2024

Yiren Jian[†], Chongyang Gao, Chen Zeng, Yunjie Zhao, Soroush Vosoughi[†]

Bootstrapping Vision-Language Learning with Decoupled Language Pre-training

[NeurIPS 2023, * spotlight] Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems

Yiren Jian, Chongyang Gao, Soroush Vosoughi

Evaluation of DNA-protein complex structures using the deep learning method

Physical Chemistry and Chemical Physics, 2023

Chengwei Zeng#, **Yiren Jian**#, Chen Zhuo, Anbang Li, Chen Zeng, Yunjie Zhao

Evaluating Native-like Structures of RNA-protein Complexes Through the Deep Learning Method

Nature Communications, 2023

Chengwei Zeng[#], **Yiren Jian**[#], Soroush Vosoughi, Chen Zeng, Yunjie Zhao

Non-Linguistic Supervision for Contrastive Learning of Sentence Embeddings

[NeurIPS 2022] Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems

Yiren Jian, Chongyang Gao, Soroush Vosoughi

T-Cell Receptor-Peptide Interaction Prediction with Physical Model Augmented Pseudo-Labeling

[KDD 2022, ** oral presentation] In Proceedings of the 28th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining

Yiren Jian, Erik Kruus, Martin Renqiang Min

Embedding Hallucination for Few-shot Language Fine-tuning

[NAACL 2022] In Proceedings of the 2022 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies

Yiren Jian, Chongyang Gao, Soroush Vosoughi

Contrastive Learning for Prompt-based Few-shot Language Learners

[NAACL 2022] In Proceedings of the 2022 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies

Yiren Jian, Chongyang Gao, Soroush Vosoughi

Label Hallucination for Few-Shot Classification

[AAAI 2022] Proceedings of the 36th AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence

Yiren Jian, Lorenzo Torresani

MetaPix: Domain Transfer for Semantic Segmentation by Meta Pixel Weighting

Image and Vision Computing, 2021

Yiren Jian, Chongyang Gao

Task Meta-Transfer from Limited Parallel Labels

Meta-Learning Workshop at Neural Information Processing Systems, 2020

Yiren Jian, Karim Ahmed, Lorenzo Torresani

DIRECT: RNA Contact Predictions by Integrating Structural Patter

BMC Bioinformatics, 2019

Yiren Jian, Xiaonan Wang, Jiadi Qiu, Huiwen Wang, Zhichao Liu, Yunjie Zhao, Chen Zeng

Trace, Machine Learning of Signal Images for Trace-Sensitive Mass Spectrometry: A Case Study from Single-Cell Metabolomics

Analytical Chemistry, 2019

Zhichao Liu, Erika P. Portero, Yiren Jian, Yunjie Zhao, Rosemary M. Onjiko, Chen Zeng, Peter Nemes

Design of Tat-activated Cdk9 Inhibitor

Journal of Peptide Research and Therapeutics, 2019

Yunjie Zhao, Hao Chen, Chenghang Du, Yiren Jian, Haotian Li, Yi Xiao, Mohammed Saifuddin, Fatah Kashanchi, and Chen Zeng

Rbind: Computational Network Method to Predict the Binding Sites of RNA Molecules

Bioinformatics, 2018

Kaili Wang[#], **Yiren Jian**[#], Huiwen Wang, Chen Zeng and Yunjie Zhao

Computational Study of Non-catalytic T-loop Pocket on CDK Proteins for Drug Development

Chinese Physics B, 2017

Huiwen Wang, Kaili Wang, Zeyu Guan, **Yiren Jian**, Ya Jia, Fatah Kashanchi, Chen Zeng, Yunjie Zhao

Network Analysis Reveals the Recognition Mechanism for Dimer Formation of Bulb-type Lectins

Scientific Report, 2017

Yunjie Zhao[#], **Yiren Jian**[#], Zhichao Liu, Hang Liu, Qin Liu, Chanyou Chen, Zhangyong Li, Lu Wang, H. Howie Huang, Chen Zeng

Patents

 $\textbf{T-cell receptor repertoire selection prediction with physical model augmented pseudo-labeling \textit{(w/ NEC Labs America)}}\\$

Academic Services _____

2024 Invited Reviewer . European Conference on Computer
--

2024 Invited Reviewer, Conference on Language Modeling

2024 Invited Reviewer, International Conference on Machine Learning

2024 Invited Reviewer, International Conference on Learning Representations

2024 Invited Reviewer, Annual AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence

2023 Invited Reviewer, Northern European Journal of Language Technology

2023 **Invited Reviewer**, IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision

2023 Invited Reviewer, Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems

2023 External Reviewer, Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics

Teaching Experience _____

2019, 2021 Graduate Teaching Assistant	Deep Learning	(graduate-	level cours	e)
--	---------------	------------	-------------	----

2021-2023 **Graduate Teaching Assistant**, Machine Learning (graduate-level course)

2018 **Graduate Teaching Assistant,** Machine Learning (graduate-level course)

2015-2016 **Graduate Teaching Assistant,** University Physics (undergraduate course)

Dartmouth

Dartmouth Dartmouth

GWU